<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Filipe Gouveia</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://filipegouveia.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Filipe Gouveia</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://filipegouveia.github.io/media/icon_hu9bb1b0438d39a79e1a914635b98f45bc_24944_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Filipe Gouveia</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/</link></image><item><title>AutoCS</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/autocs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/autocs/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Ref. EP/V040340/1&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Financed by:&lt;/strong> EPSRC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Awarded to:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.andrewcropper.com/" target="_blank" >Andrew Cropper&lt;/a> at the University of Oxford&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Building machines that automatically write computer programs is a long-standing grand challenge in AI. Such a development would offer the potential to build bug-free and efficient programs without required specialist knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To work towards this grand challenge, this project will build on major recent breakthroughs in Inductive Logic Programming (ILP), a form of machine learning based on mathematical logic. Because of these breakthroughs, ILP currently has the ability of a first-year computer science student: given much guidance, it can learn simple algorithms and build small programs. This project aims to advance ILP to the level of a computer science PhD student so that given little guidance it can discover novel and complex algorithms and build large programs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a marker of success, a key objective is to use an AutoCS to discover a novel algorithm and publish it in a computer science journal. Such a result would be a landmark achievement for AI and would herald a new era of automatic scientific discovery.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="members">Members&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.andrewcropper.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Andrew Cropper&lt;/a> (PI)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://celinehocquette.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Céline Hocquette&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://filipegouveia.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Filipe Gouveia&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>RIGA</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/riga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/riga/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Refª 2022.03537.PTDC&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Type:&lt;/strong> National Project&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Financed by:&lt;/strong> FCT&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Prime Contractor:&lt;/strong> R - INESC-ID Lisboa (Other) - Lisboa, Portugal&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project RIGA aims to propose the use of automated reasoning to identify proxy attributes in training datasets without prior background knowledge of the relations between attributes. In project RIGA it is not only desired to identify single attributes that act as proxy attributes of a given protected attribute, but also combinations of attributes that act as proxy attributes. In the latter case, it is considered that two or more unprotected attributes combined act as proxy attributes, where each one of these attributes individually are not proxy attributes. This raises a challenging combinatorial problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal of project RIGA is the application of logic-based approaches to identify potential proxy attributes (single or combined) in datasets that can lead to discriminatory Machine Learning models. In the identification of proxy attributes, different relations between unprotected and protected attributes are considered, such as equivalence and implication. Moreover, it is considered that a proxy attribute may have a degree of confidence associated. For example, if it is not possible to infer accurately all the values (100%) of a protected attribute from the information of a set of unprotected attributes, but it is possible to infer most of the values (e.g. 90 %), then one may want to consider such set of unprotected attributes as proxy attributes as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="members">Members&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://sat.inesc-id.pt/~ines/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Inês Lynce&lt;/a> (PI)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://filipegouveia.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Filipe Gouveia&lt;/a> (Co-PI)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://sat.inesc-id.pt/~vmm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vasco Manquinho&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Model Revision of Boolean Logical Models of Biological Regulatory Networks</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/theses/phd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/theses/phd/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ModRev - Model Revision Tool for Boolean Logical Models of Biological Regulatory Networks</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2020/cmsb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2020/cmsb/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Semi-automatic model revision of Boolean regulatory networks: confronting time-series observations with (a)synchronous dynamics</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2020/biorxiv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2020/biorxiv/</guid><description/></item><item><title>GOLEM</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/golem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/golem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Ref: LISBOA-01-0247-FEDER-045917&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ultimate goal of GOLEM is to find a sustainable solution for the increasing need for complex enterprise digital systems and the lack of people with enough technical skills for creating them. We believe that the only realistic long term solution to this problem is to automate insofar as possible the creation of such systems. In doing so, not only the creation of enterprise software is sped up, but also, and more importantly, people with non-programming backgrounds are granted the opportunity to participate in the digitization effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the GOLEM project, new software development approaches will be explored, building on what we believe to be the state of the art of rapid and easy enterprise software development: low-code platforms, in particular, the world leading OutSystems development platform. Like all other low-code solutions on the market, even though the OutSystems platform enables great productivity and short development cycles through visual development and deployment automation, it still requires knowledge about programming and software architectures that only experienced software developers have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The GOLEM project aims to enable non-programmers to develop enterprise-grade applications by evolving the OutSystems low-code development model to a new fully integrated and interactive development experience in which programming is automated, based on natural language specifications, examples given by the developer, point and click demonstrations, or sketches. The output of that automation is not only code but also a live preview of the application&amp;rsquo;s behavior that allows the developer to understand the effects of his actions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Revision of Boolean Models of Regulatory Networks Using Stable State Observations</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2020/jcb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2020/jcb/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Model revision of boolean regulatory networks at stable state</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2019/isbra/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2019/isbra/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Model revision of logical regulatory networks using logic-based tools</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2018/iclp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2018/iclp/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ModRev</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/modrev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/modrev/</guid><description>&lt;p>ModRev is a command line tool to revise Boolean logical models of biological regulatory networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tool was developed for &lt;em>UNIX&lt;/em> and &lt;em>MacOSX&lt;/em> systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ModRev&lt;/strong> is able to repair inconsistent Boolean models under the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Set of stable state observations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set of time-series observations
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>With synchronous update scheme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>With asynchronous update scheme&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Logic-Based Encodings for Ricochet Robots</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2017/epia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/2017/epia/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Protein design using answer set programming</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/theses/msc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/publication/theses/msc/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/teaching/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>