<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mentalhealth on Filipe Gouveia</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/tags/mentalhealth/</link><description>Recent content in Mentalhealth on Filipe Gouveia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© Filipe Gouveia</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/tags/mentalhealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Productivity Check</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/posts/2024-04/productivity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/posts/2024-04/productivity/</guid><description>Mental health is a serious thing. I never expected to be in a situation like this. I think that most people will think that this is nothing and that there is so many people in worse situations. I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree. But this is still something for me. And for now, it is all that matters.
The last years had been a nightmare for me. A lot have change, personally and professionally.</description><content>&lt;p>Mental health is a serious thing. I never expected to be in a situation like this. I think that most people will think that this is nothing and that there is so many people in worse situations. I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree. But this is still something for me. And for now, it is all that matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last years had been a nightmare for me. A lot have change, personally and professionally. I lost someone very, very dear to me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also changed to a different country to work in a new job. So I found myself in a new place, alone, far from home. I never allowed myself time to deal with my loss, specially to be able to be strong for my family, helping them, be the rational one, and deal with the bureaucratic stuff. Moreover, I found myself pushing everything down, while studying new things for this new job. Everything looked okay&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the beginning everything was good at work. I was very excited, and I was getting good results, being productive in a new scenario. However, after a few months of this new life, I&amp;rsquo;ve been warned that I was starting to progress slower at work. Of course that I have good days and bad days, some days I am more productive than others, I think that is natural. At least I think it is. However, looking back, reflecting of what I have done, I noticed that I had been, indeed, slower. And that is what is most scary for me. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even realise it! I have no idea where did the time go. And it is not lack of motivation, because I have been able to contribute positively to my work, and I have been very excited with the results. I like what I do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My only possible explanation is that I have been pushing things down for so long, that I have been so worried and concerned about everything and everyone else, that after some time all these changes, and the fact that I never truly processed them, started to affect me. I found myself sometimes running all these hypothetical scenarios on my head, all these conversations that never happened (and most likely never will). My mind just goes, thinking of all the problems, of all the issues. Maybe this is the cause. My mind going away thinking of something, and the time goes by without even noticing it. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I am the only one that does this. That starts thinking of all these hypothetical scenarios that can occur, all the possible conversations. All the possible reactions for all the things that I can say or do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what scares me, is not being slow or being less productive. I know what I am worth, I know what I can do, I know my value. I am not concerned about my job. I like it a lot and it is a great opportunity, for sure, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to loose it. But, if that happens, I understand. But I have to deal with this issue. I want to solve this issue. What scares me is that I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise it was an issue. I had to be told.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I took some days off. Try to clear my mind. Let go. Just let go of all the problems, concerns, worries. Just be. Focusing on myself, what I wanted to do, or not do. Just let it go, day by day. I think it worked, in the sense that I could ease myself, think less of all the problems and issues that I have to deal with personally. But I am left wondering. How can I keep a check on myself? How can I improve? How many people go through similar situations? And how can I be more productive? How can I &amp;lsquo;force&amp;rsquo; myself to focus? (I have tried a lot of things and apps&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to make them truly work.)&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>