<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Filipe Gouveia</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/tags/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Filipe Gouveia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© Filipe Gouveia</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/tags/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/about/</guid><description>I am currently an Invited Assistant Professor at the Faculty of Sciences of the University of Lisbon.
Previously, from 2024 to 2025, I worked at SISCOG as a Software Enginnering, applying Boolean Satisfiability to generate train schedules. I was a Research Associate, during 2023-2024, at the Department of Computer Science of the University of Oxford in the Logic and Learning (LOL) group, in the field of Inductive Logic Programming. I was also a researcher at INESC-ID Lisboa in the Automated Reasoning and Software Reliability (ARSR) group, during 2016-2023.</description><content>&lt;p>I am currently an Invited Assistant Professor at the Faculty of Sciences of the University of Lisbon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously, from 2024 to 2025, I worked at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->SISCOG&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> as a Software Enginnering, applying Boolean Satisfiability to generate train schedules.
I was a Research Associate, during 2023-2024, at the Department of Computer Science of the University of Oxford in the Logic and Learning (LOL) group, in the field of Inductive Logic Programming.
I was also a researcher at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->INESC-ID Lisboa&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> in the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Automated Reasoning and Software Reliability (ARSR)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> group, during 2016-2023.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I obtained an MSc in Information Systems and Computer Engineering from &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->IST - Universidade de Lisboa&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> in 2012, focussing on intelligent systems, and information technology.
Then, I worked in the private sector for some years, as a software developer. Here, I participated in several projects, developing, for example, geographical information systems web services, and thematic websites.
In 2021, I obtained a Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering from &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->IST - Universidade de Lisboa&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->, being approved with distinction.
During my Ph.D., I was awarded with a doctoral grant from &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Fundação para a Ciência e Tecnologia (FCT)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->. My Ph.D work focused on the application of logic-based approaches and algorithms to revise Boolean logical models of biological regulatory networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></content></item></channel></rss>