<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Filipe Gouveia</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Filipe Gouveia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© Filipe Gouveia</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Part of Me</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/posts/2024-06/partofme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/terminal/posts/2024-06/partofme/</guid><description>A year ago part of me passed away with him.
Nothing was left undone, nothing left unsaid.
We knew exactly what we meant to each other, such was our complicity. He used to say that I was his more than friend, his doctor. He knew that I hate being called by my title, but he did it jokingly, but never able to hide the pride in his eyes.
I enjoyed every moment, I did everything I could, I spent every bit of available time in his company.</description><content>&lt;p>A year ago part of me passed away with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing was left undone, nothing left unsaid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We knew exactly what we meant to each other, such was our complicity.
He used to say that I was his more than friend, his doctor.
He knew that I hate being called by my title, but he did it jokingly, but never able to hide the pride in his eyes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed every moment, I did everything I could, I spent every bit of available time in his company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Part of me died with him, but part of him will always live inside me.
An inexplicable exchange.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He was, is, and will be, as long as there are people who remember him, a true example of a human being.
I can only keep him present by following his example, hoping that one day I can be half the person he is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing I&amp;rsquo;m sure of, it&amp;rsquo;s that we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t regret what was left to be said or done, but rather take advantage of every moment to say and do before it&amp;rsquo;s too late.
I have nothing to regret, nothing was left unsaid, nothing left undone.
I just have to thank the privilege that I have in calling such a wonderful person my &lt;strong>grandfather&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>