<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GOLEM | Filipe Gouveia</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/tag/golem/</link><atom:link href="https://filipegouveia.github.io/tag/golem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>GOLEM</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://filipegouveia.github.io/media/icon_hufa4c56891d61cfa37a39b89fe3e36f4b_30358_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>GOLEM</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/tag/golem/</link></image><item><title>GOLEM</title><link>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/golem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://filipegouveia.github.io/project/golem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Ref: LISBOA-01-0247-FEDER-045917&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ultimate goal of GOLEM is to find a sustainable solution for the increasing need for complex enterprise digital systems and the lack of people with enough technical skills for creating them. We believe that the only realistic long term solution to this problem is to automate insofar as possible the creation of such systems. In doing so, not only the creation of enterprise software is sped up, but also, and more importantly, people with non-programming backgrounds are granted the opportunity to participate in the digitization effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the GOLEM project, new software development approaches will be explored, building on what we believe to be the state of the art of rapid and easy enterprise software development: low-code platforms, in particular, the world leading OutSystems development platform. Like all other low-code solutions on the market, even though the OutSystems platform enables great productivity and short development cycles through visual development and deployment automation, it still requires knowledge about programming and software architectures that only experienced software developers have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The GOLEM project aims to enable non-programmers to develop enterprise-grade applications by evolving the OutSystems low-code development model to a new fully integrated and interactive development experience in which programming is automated, based on natural language specifications, examples given by the developer, point and click demonstrations, or sketches. The output of that automation is not only code but also a live preview of the application&amp;rsquo;s behavior that allows the developer to understand the effects of his actions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>